# Yuan LYU

# **UX/Interaction Designer**

### **EXPERIENCE**

- UX/UI Design Intern, Volkswagen AG
   Smart Mobility&Transport, Berlin, Germany
   Oct.2018 ~ Present
  - Iterate the UX design, conduct wireframe, mockups for user test
  - Master the persona profile, customer journey, user flow of product
  - Create the UI library, redesign and implement the landing page
  - Innovation Intern, F. Hoffmann La-Roche AG
    Finance, Diagnostics IT, Basel, Switzerland Nov.2017 ~ Apr. 2018
    - Contributed to key internal projects as UX Designer, analysis business needs and transfer to the functional solutions
    - Designed and implemented the UCD curriculum, drove cross-team knowledge building agenda on usability
    - Created and facilitated Design Sprint workshop
- Master Thesis Student, Technische Universität Berlin
  Quality and Usability Lab, Berlin, Germany Jul.2017 ~ May.2018

  Concept Design for Pedestrian-Vehicle Communication in the Age
  of Autonomous Driving
  - Product Design Working Student, Care Campanion GmbH.

    Product Team, Berlin, Germany

    Jul.2017 ~ Oct.2017
    - Concepting and designing for main website and new landing page
    - Analyzing user journey, preparing&executing user research activities
    - Co-operating with senior designer, product managers and developer
  - UX Strategist, Co-founder, Transmetics

Paris, France

Sept.2015 ~ May.2016

Transmetics is a mobile APP which can help foreigners to buy suitable cosmetics in France. I contributed mainly on design research, UX/service design and Android development.

**UX Intern**, FOTILE Kitchen Ware Co. Ltd.

Innovation Institute, Ningbo, China

Oct.2014 ~ Jan.2015

- Co-designed interface for new oven, steam box and microwave oven
- Implement the high-fidelity Prototype individually
- Made reasonable user test script, participated in usability research

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Human Computer Interaction and Design

Double Degree ♀ EIT Digital Merit Scholarship 2016/2017

Technische Universität Berlin, Germany 2016 ~ 2018 Université Paris-Sud, France 2015 ~ 2016

**Bachelor of Engineering in Network Engineering** 

Dalian Maritime University, China 2011 ~ 2015

- **+49(0)157-3326-2956**
- yuan.lyu@hotmail.com
- http://yuan-lyu.com
- Berlin, Germany 10963

## **PROFILE**

As a hybrid UX designer with programming experiences, I am adept at understanding of user story, and always have the passion to use my creativity to solve unusual problems and design for uncommon products.

Sincerely look forward to the position in the area of UX and Interaction Design.

## **SKILLS**

#### **DESIGN**

In-Depth Interview
Questionnaire
Persona | Scenario
Conceptual Storyboard
Wireframing
Prototyping
Usability Test
Sketch / Photoshop
Axure / InVision / Principle
Balsamiq / OmniGraffle

#### **PROGRAMMING**

JAVA / C#
HTML / CSS / JavaScript
Bootstrap
ASP.NET
SQL Server / MySQL
Unity (Virtual Reality)
Arduino / Processing
Node.js

#### **LANGUAGE**

Chinese: Native English: Fluent German: Beginner